BRIAN MONT ENERGY CONSULTANT

- briansmont830@gmail.com
- www.brianmont.com
- **4** 2017073742
- **♀** Philadelphia, PA
- **O** briansmont

I have been working in commodity sales and consulting for 5 years developing business and marketing abilities. Over the past year I have worked hard to develop an understanding of web development and UI/UX design. I'm looking for a position in this industry to learn more and work at an exciting new company.

Skills

BUSINESS SKILLS

Direct Sales, Business Development, Marketing, Public Speaking, Data Auditing, Strategy Development

TECH SKILLS

Javascript, HTML, CSS, AngularJS, JQuery, Ruby, Rails, JSON, Git, CLI, React, Outlook, Powerpoint, Word, Excel

Education

The College of New Jersey Major Business Administration 2011 Minor Finance 2011

Bloc

Front/Back End Web Development 2017

Employment

LD Energy Consulting

Rochelle Park, NJ Dec 2012 to Current, Dec 2012 to Current

Director of Operations Dec 2012 to Current, Dec 2012 to Current, Pec 2012 to Current, Dec 201

Create marketing plans based on market research and industry intelligence.

Audit weekly usage and commission reports to ensure all payments and services are rendered in a timely manner.

Account Executive

Jan 2012 to Current

Booked more than \$3 million in gross sales in electricity and natural gas contracting. Negotiated forward prices in commodities to present the best strategies and products to fit each client's diverse needs.

Led face to face presentations with high level decision makers and executive boards.

Projects

Angular & React Front End Metrics

Nov 2016 to Dec 2016

Refactored an AngularJS/JQuery music app I previously built to track user events. Added event listeners to track song plays, completions, and other user input. Implemented ReactJS rendering to display metric data in charts for easy review.

ReactJS To-Do Application

Dec 2016 to Jan 2017

Built a functional to-do application for users to submit data via a form, which saves to a database and renders to the view.

Implemented github OAuth, allowing users to access private data.

Developed a React component which filters through saved data and checks for status and specific text.

Refactored storage using Redux to simplify state mangement throughout all components.

Wiki Application

Sep 2016 to Oct 2016

Developed a Rails application where users have full CRUD capability over wiki pages. Configured gems to allow authentications, automate email confirmations, and address user roles.

Managed and accessed database through Active Record, SQL, and rails migrations.